星际之门亚特兰蒂斯  前情回顾
Previously on stargate atlantis...
这是什么东西
what is it?
总有一天  这能让我们对幽灵族完全免疫
Something that will one day make us completely immune to the wraith.
我们打算用你的囚犯
We want to test the serum's effectiveness
测试血清的效果
Against your prisoner.
我们说的是把一个人类
We're talking about
与一名饥饿的幽灵人
Putting a human being in the same room
关在同一间屋子里
As a starving wraith.
一名晚期的重症患者自愿
The test subject is a terminally ill patient
做这次测试的对象
Who has volunteered himself.
你对我做了什么
What have you done to me?
我们正在追踪飞马星系上
Now we've been tracking what appears to be
一例新变种疾病
A new sickness in the pegasus galaxy.
这种始于霍夫星上居民的
It's a unique protein originally created
独特蛋白质
By the inhabitants of a planet called hoff.
它被设计于干涉幽灵族的
It was designed to interfere
捕食机制
With the wraith's feeding mechanism,
使得他们对捕食过程免疫
Making them immune to the process.
它也会使捕食的幽灵人
It also killed the feeding wraith
和半数接种人类致死
And half the people who took it.
大家可别忘了
Well, let's not forget
迈克尔把这种经过修改的hoffan药
That michael spread the modified hoffan drug
散播到几十个甚至更多的星球
To dozens of worlds, possibly more.
我的意思是  谁也不清楚具体数目吧
I mean, no one knows for sure, right?
这意味着你们每次捕食
Which means that every time you feed,
都是在冒风险
You're taking a risk.
再来一次
Once more.
是你的坏消息啊
Bad news, I'm afraid.
明天你可要返校了
You'll have to go back to school tomorrow.
阿莫西林再持续服用三天
Maintain the amoxicillin for three more days.
就可以彻底康复
That should do the trick.
你这儿怎么了
Now, what do we have over here?
得重新换药了
All these dressings need to be changed.
可以去储藏室
Do you mind going back to the storeroom
拿点绷带过来吗
And getting some more bandages, please?
没问题  医生
Yes, doctor.
谢谢  另外
Thank you. besides that,
你看上去好多了  伙计
You're looking good, my friend.
邮件到了
Mail call.
中校
Colonel!
你们都来这儿干什么
What are you all doing here?
我们听说你需要些日常补给
Well, we heard you needed supplies,
所以就送过来些  顺便看看你近况如何
So we thought we'd come by and see how you were doing.
经历飞行 跳跃  还要穿越星门
A "hop, skip, and a jump from the gate"?
这也叫顺便过来啊
That's what you call that?
很高兴见到你  罗德尼
Nice to see you too, rodney.
最近还好吗  医生
How are you, doctor?
还不错  谢谢关心
Well, thanks.
这些应该就是我要的抗生素吧
I take it these are the antibiotics I ordered?
凯勒医生给的可不少
Dr. keller gave you a whole whack of them,
够你用一些日子了
So they should last for a while.
上帝  希望是真的
Ah, god, I wish that were true.
什么意思
What does that mean?
我最近一直在治疗
Well, I've been dealing with
Hoffan瘟疫幸存者带来的大量传染病
A number of infections from the hoffan plague survivors.
我只能勉勉强强应付得来
I can barely keep on top of it.
这里有Hoffan瘟疫幸存者?
Survivors of the hoffan plague here?
这个星球不在迈克尔的目标之列吧
This is not one of the planets that michael targeted.
是的  但这儿有很多人
No, but many of these people
都是从另一个叫巴拉的星球上来的
Actually come from another planet, balar.
他们成功从瘟疫中存活了下来
They managed to survive the plague,
但就在他们族人重新聚集
And just when they're starting
开始生活的时候
To get their pieces back together,
幽灵人出现了
The wraith showed up,
力图将他们赶尽杀绝
Tried to wipe them out.
我们听到过类似的传闻
Mm, we heard rumors about that.
幽灵人很不乐意
Well, the wraith aren't too pleased
有人能够免疫于
To have whole populations out there
他们的吸食啊
That are immune to their feeding.
只有少数的巴拉人存活了下来
Just a handful of the balarans survived.
当地人很善良的接纳了他们
The locals were kind enough to take them in.
医生
Doctor?
诺瓦
Novo!
这些是从亚特兰蒂斯来得朋友
These are my friends from atlantis.
谢帕德·中校  泰勒  若男
Colonel sheppard, teyla, ronon,
罗德尼·麦凯博士
And dr. rodney mckay.
这位是诺瓦
This is novo.
一直在我的诊所里帮忙
She's been helping me here in the clinic.
很高兴见到你
Pleasure to meet you.
我也是  我听到过很多关于你们的事
You as well. I've heard a lot about you.
他就是那个人吗
Is he the one?
那个人?
The one what?
众多妙趣横生的故事都有你
From all the funny stories.
对了
Right!
大家都留下来吃晚饭吧
Yeah, well, I hope you all can stay here for dinner?
这里的食堂不算豪华
I mean, the canteen's not fancy,
不过他们用一种类似于山羊的
But they do serve up one heck of a stew,
生物炖的菜
Made from a goat-like creature.
味道好极了
Delicious!
类似于山羊?
Goat-like?
这主意不错
I think it's a great idea.
正好让我们有机会回忆下
Gives us a chance to catch up
那些..."妙趣横生的故事"
And relive all those... "funny stories."
在飞马星系这样的荒芜地带过得怎样啊
So how's life in the wilds of pegasus?
会怀念亚特兰蒂斯吧
You got to be missing atlantis by now.
令人惊讶地是  没有
Surprisingly, no.
得了吧
Oh, come on.
就不会想热水澡  游戏机  除臭剂
The hot baths, playstation, deodorant?
这儿可能看起来有点简陋
I know it seems a wee bit rough,
但事实上不是
But it's not, really.
不论在哪里  人们都对我很友好
Wherever I go, people are kind to me.
我一直都是衣食无忧
I never want for a meal or a place to sleep.
实话对你说
And to be honest with you,
我现在才真正感觉到
I'm really starting to feel like
我也可以贡献一份力量了
I'm making a difference.
怎么了
What is it?
幽灵人
Wraith.
有九个敌人
I count nine of 'em.
我们能搞定
We can take 'em.
不行  这里平民太多了
No. there's too many civilians.
这似乎不是平常的捕食
It does not appear to be an ordinary culling.
你怎么知道
How do you figure that?
首先  天上没有幽灵战机
Well, for one thing, there are no darts,
而且他们也没有要攻击村民的迹象
And they do not seem to be attacking the villagers.
你们之中谁说了算
Who among you speaks for the rest?
我是埃尔森
I'm elson...
这里的村长
Leader of this village.
你来这里有何贵干
What do you want with us?
你们最近收容了
You've recently taken in
其他星球上的一些难民
A group of refugees from another planet.
他们是瘟疫的幸存者
They are survivors of a plague.
你必须马上把他们交给我
It's important that you turn them over to me immediately.
为什么
Why?
你不需要知道原因
The reasons why do not concern you.
你要是肯定合作
Provided you cooperate,
我们会和平撤离
You have my word we will leave peacefully.
如果我们不呢
And if we don't?
那可不是个好决定
That would be a very unwise decision.
我们的蜂巢战舰会在黄昏前抵达
Our hive will be here before the night is through.
如果你执迷不悟
If you have not complied by then,
别怪我不客气了
I will give the word,
你的村庄会毁于一旦
And your entire village will be destroyed.
交出外来人
Turn over these outsiders,
就绕你们一命
And your lives will be spared.
抵抗的话
Resist,
就跟他们一块死吧
And you will all die together.
你看着办
The choice is yours.
我不明白
I don't understand.
他们都已经把我们家园毁了
They've already destroyed our homeworld.
为什么还要赶尽杀绝呢
Why would they hunt the rest of us down as well?
你没告诉他们?
You didn't tell them?
没彻底说明
Not the whole story.
你们在说什么
What are you talking about?
诺瓦  记得我告诉过你
Novo, remember when I told you that,
作为一个瘟疫的幸存者
As a plague survivor,
你们可以对幽灵人的捕食功能免疫
You'd be immune to the wraith feeding?
其实不仅仅是那样
Well, there's a bit more to it than that.
任何幽灵人企图捕食你或者类似的人时
Any wraith who tries to feed on you, or anyone like you,
其结果都是  他们立刻死亡
Will, as a result, die instantly.
你对他们来言是毒药
You're poison to them.
也就是说我们跟死了一样
Then we're as good as dead.
不一定
Not necessarily.
如果你们说得是真的
They won't tolerate our presence anywhere.
幽灵人不会容忍我们存在世上
Not if what you say is true.
那是因为他们在这里发现了你们
Just because they found you on this world
并不意味你们不能有其他藏身之处
Does not mean that there is nowhere you can hide.
诺瓦
Novo?
听说了吗
Did you hear?
是的
Yes.
这是塞法里斯  也是巴拉星人
This is sefaris. he's also from balar.
村里的议员们正在讨论
The councilors are meeting to discuss
是否遵从幽灵人的要求
Whether or not to heed the wraith's request.
什么  哪里
What? where?
在矿工办公室
The mine office.
我试图进去  可是他们不让
I tried to get in, but they turned me away.
若男和泰勒  去视察星门周围
Ronon and teyla, scope out the gate.
你们俩在这呆着
You two stay here.
照顾下他们
Watch these people.
能告诉我那个办公室在哪里吗
Can you show me where this mine office is?
没问题
Yes.
中校  你打算怎么跟他们说
Colonel, what are you going to say to them?
我去给他们指条明路
I'm going to give them another way out.
你是说  经历过这场瘟疫
You're telling us that, as a result of this plague,
巴拉星人变成了幽灵人的致命毒药
The balarans are now deadly to the wraith?
差不多
Pretty much.
所以幽灵人不会冒险
So the wraith would never risk
洗劫村子
Culling this village?
的确如此
Mm, that's true,
这也正是为什么他们希望
But that's also why they're willing
将你们赶尽杀绝的原因
To wipe you guys out completely.
一个无法洗劫的村子对他们可不是好事
A village that can't be culled is no good to them.
他们知道吗
Did they know?
什么
What?
巴拉人来这之前知道
Did the balarans know
他们的到来
They were bringing this curse upon us
为我们带来诅咒吗
When they came here?
不  他们懵然不知
No. they had no idea.
错不在他们   杰维斯
It's not their fault, jervis.
或许吧
Maybe not,
不过也无关重要了
But that doesn't matter.
除非这个银河系
The wraith won't rest
最后一个残存的人也断气  否则幽灵人不会善罢甘休
Until every last plague survivor in this galaxy is dead.
现在幽灵人对于他们的行踪毫无头绪
Except the wraith have no idea who they are
除非你们众人把他们供出来
Unless people like you point them out.
中校  我也不希望发生这样的事
I'm not happy about this either, colonel,
但我们还有别的选择吗
But what other choice do we have?
或许我们可以把你的人民
We may be able to move all your people
转移到别的星球
To a different planet,
一个安全的地方
Where they'll be safe.
你要我们离开家园?
You mean leave our homes?
我知道这不好受
I know it's not ideal,
但剩下的唯一选择就是
But the only other choice
供出那些清白无辜的人
Is to turn in a bunch of innocent people,
你们也不愿意做这个吧
And I know you guys aren't going to do that, right?
正如幽灵人所说  他们是外人
Well, as the wraith said, they're outsiders.
杰维斯
Jervis,
我们达成共识  让他们进来
We agreed to let them come here.
我没有
I didn't agree.
再者  那时他们还没造成威胁
Besides, they weren't a threat at the time.
如今大势已变
Now that's changed.
但他们已成了我们的一份子
But they've become like family.
诺瓦跟我同一个屋檐下生活
Novo lives under my roof.
同一张桌子上吃饭
She eats at my table.
我女儿很喜欢她
My daughter adores her.
你叫我怎么跟她说
What am I supposed to tell her?
难道你要我们全去送死
You'd prefer that we all be killed?
谢帕德中校  有情况
Colonel sheppard, come in.
失陪
Excuse me.
说
Go ahead.
若楠和我在星门附近
Ronon and I are at the gate.
那里的守卫尚不算森严
It does not appear to be heavily guarded.
是村庄看到的那帮人
It's the same guys from the village.
我认出他们的指挥官
I recognize the commander.
靠近他们的几率大吗
What are the odds of you two getting by 'em?
挺大的
Pretty good.
事实上  微乎其微
Slim, actually,
如果你和罗德尼也来  成数会高点
But much better if you and rodney join us.
那好吧
Yeah, all right.
我们到之前先按兵不动
Hold your position till we can get there.
怎么了
What is it?
这个村庄有多少口人
How many people are in this village?
600到700
600, 700.
时间可能有点紧  但我们尽量安排
Well, we'll be tight for time, but we can manage.
你有什么计划
What are you suggesting?
我们去引开幽灵人
We take the wraith out,
在蜂巢战舰到之前  让所有人穿过星门
Get everybody through the gate before the hive ship comes.
在我们重新安置你们之前  留在亚特兰蒂斯应该很安全
You should be safe in atlantis till we can relocate you.
无法接受
Unacceptable.
巴拉族不应受到如此对待
The balarans don't deserve this.
他们只是疾病的幸存者
They did nothing but survive a sickness.
有朝一日  我们也会如此
It could just as easily have happened to us.
如果我们供出他们
If we turn these people over,
我们就和凶残的幽灵人无异
We are no better than the wraith ourselves.
听着
Look.
即使你和幽灵人合作
Even if you cooperate with the wraith,
也不能保证
There's no guarantee
他们会信守诺言
They're going to keep their word.
也许他们会把你们全杀了  免得碍手碍脚
They may just kill all of you for being an inconvenience.
好吧
All right.
我们要做什么
What do you want us to do?
准备好转移
Be ready to move.
带上必需品
Take only what you can carry.
罗德尼  跟我走  我们去袭击幽灵人
Let's go, rodney. we're going to hit the wraith.
我们?
We are?
我跟你一起去
I'll come with you.
医生  别
Not a chance, doc.
中校
Colonel--
我没时间解释了
I don't have time to argue.
另外  还要组织大家转移
Get these people ready for transport.
当星门安全之后
Once the gate's secure,
我们要尽快行动
We're going to have to move fast.
好的  万事小心
Okay, but be careful.
如果要袭击
If we're going to attack,
得从那边开始
We got to do it from over there.
没错
Agreed.
一旦我们夺回星门
As soon as we take the gate,
得召些飞船来
We should call in some jumpers.
有助于撤空这里的村民
It'll make evacuating the village a lot faster.
加上我们可以运用飞船上的火力
Not to mention we can use the extra firepower
以防在转移过程中战舰提早到来
In case the hive gets here before we're done.
希望不要走到这一步
Oh, let's hope it doesn't come to that.
谢帕德中校  有情况
Colonel sheppard, come in.
说
Go ahead.
我们遇到难题了
We have a problem.
越来越多的幽灵人聚集在星门处
More of the wraith have begun arriving back.
他们一定是外出巡逻来了
They must have been out on patrol.
有多少
How many?
有机会突围吗
Can we still get out?
没有  我的意思是  我们被困了
No.from what i mean we're stuck here
你说  你能带我们走
You said you could get us out.
幽灵人的数目比我想的要多
Well, there are more wraith than we thought.
星门守卫森严
The gate's too heavily guarded.
我们被困了?
So we're trapped?
现在
For the moment.
我还没放弃希望
I haven't given up hope.
只是需要些许时间  拟定新的作战计划
I just need time to develop a new strategy.
你能制定什么计划
What strategy do you propose
来对付幽灵人大军
We use to defeat an army of wraith?
暂时不知道
Well, I don't know.
我还没仔细考虑
I haven't thought of it yet.
听着
Look,
最坏打算  如过我的组员和我再不回去
Worst-case scenario-- my team and I don't show up,
亚特兰蒂斯的人会利用星门拨号
The people back on atlantis will dial the gate
用无线电联系我们
And contact us by radio.
我们可以叫援兵
I can order back-up.
能赶在战舰来之前召集援兵吗
Will that happen before the hive ship arrives?
可能不会
Probably not.
我们等不了那么久
We can't wait that long.
就我们所知
For all we know,
幽灵人可能对战舰夸大其词
The wraith could be lying about the ship.
他们为什么要这么做
And why would they do that?
我说的是
I'm just saying,
我们要尽可能地拖延时间
We need to stall as long as possible.
这是疯子的行为
This is madness.
伊森  我们不能把
Elson, we have to think
村民的安全置之不理
Of the safety of our people.
我一直考虑的都是你们的安危
Oh, I'm thinking about the safety of your people.
你们全村的人
All your people!
我们不能指望他们的帮助
We can't rely on their help.
我们要自己做主
We have to make our own decisions.
我要时间好好考虑
I need time to think about this.
伊森  时间紧迫
The time for that has passed, elson.
我们得行动
We have to act.
如果你还犹豫不决
And if you're not prepared to do so,
我自己来做
Then I will.
杰维斯
Jervis!
他要做什么
What's he going to do?
我不知道
I don't know.
诺瓦和别的人哪去了
Where's novo and the others?
我们叫他们回去了  怎么了
We sent them home. why?
他们可以行走吗
Can these people walk?
应该可以
Well, if need be,
但我觉得  他们不能穿越星门
But I thought we couldn't get them through the gate.
我也认为如此  时间太紧了
No, we can't for the time being,
但留下也不安全
But I don't think they're safe here either.
拿起武器
Grab your weapons.
跟我来
Come with me.
让开
Get out of my way.
她不在这里  杰维斯
She's not here, jervis.
她在哪
Where is she?
我们该怎办  诺瓦
What are we going to do, novo?
我们得离开这个村子
We have to get out of the village.
外面发生什么事
What the hell's going on out there?
部分村民
Some of the villagers
决定自扫门前雪
Decided to take matters into their own hands.
我们去制止他们
Well, let's go stop 'em.
当务之急
First things first.
我们要撤离村民  拿些工具
We got to move these people. grab some gear.
我们不想惹事端
We don't want any trouble.
只要供出巴拉族人的下落
Just hand over the balarans.
我不认同
I don't think so.
中校  别让我难做
Don't make things difficult, colonel.
你错过了拯救村民的机会
You had your chance to save the village.
是时候让我挺身而出
Now it's my turn.
拯救村庄  你是这么认为的吗
Saving the village? that's what you call this?
你少管闲事
This isn't your affair.
这件事该怎么处理  是我们的事
It's up to us to decide how to deal with the situation.
是的  没错
Yes, it is,
杰维斯  但这不是我们的做法
But jervis, this is not our way.
我们的做法?
Our way?
我们的做法就是
Our way is what got us into this situation
自找麻烦
In the first place!
我们对他们已经是
We've already given them
仁至义尽
More than they could have ever asked for.
好吧
All right,
为何不将他们都杀了
Why not just shoot them right now
干脆了事
And get it over with?
横也是死  竖也是死
It's a death sentence anyway.
现在杀了他们
Shoot them yourself,
免得他们还要遭受
And spare them the torment
幽灵人的折磨
Of being tortured by the wraith.
你反倒帮了他们个大忙
You'd be doing them a favor.
卡森
Carson.
来吧  杀光他们
Go on! kill them all, then,
你当真如此想摆脱他们
If you're that desperate to be done with them!
你们犯大错了
You're making a big mistake.
或者吧
Maybe,
至少我们问心无愧
But at least we do so with a clear conscience.
已经无关重要了
Doesn't matter anyway.
你什么意思
What are you talking about?
我的手下已经把刚抓到的人
My men are already on the way to the gate
押往星门
With the first group we captured.
为时已晚
It's too late.
他们要对我们怎样
What are they going to do to us?
冷静点  塞法里斯  别吓着别人
Be calm, sefaris. you're scaring the others.
或许他们应该害怕
Maybe they should be scared.
我们都知道  这次我们无路可逃
We both know there's no escape from this.
我们不能放弃希望
We cannot give up hope.
勇敢地面对它  诺瓦
Face it, novo...
他们背叛了我们
We've been betrayed.
他们不想我们待在这里  一直视我们为外人
They don't want us here.They never did.
当我们离开自己家的时候就注定玩完了
We were doomed the moment we had to leave our homes.
想到...
And, to think...
作为幸存者
As a survivor,
我还一度以为自己是幸运的
I used to consider myself one of the lucky ones.
看好杰维斯没?
Is jervis taken care of?
他和那些人都被关起来了
He and his men have been locked up.
他们不会再惹麻烦了
They will not be giving us any more trouble,
尽管我觉得没必要打晕他们
Though I do not think it was necessary to stun them.
但那样感觉更好
Felt good, though.
现在怎么样
So what now?
我们要把剩下的巴拉人
Well, I got to get the rest of the balarans
迁移出村
Out of the village.
没有任何证据说
There's no telling if anybody else
其他人就不会有杰维斯这样的想法
Might feel the way jervis does.
那我们带他们去哪儿
Where should we take them?
森林里?
The forest?
大半夜的  那可要拖很远
It's kind of a long haul at night.
等一下  矿井怎么样
Wait a minute. what about the mine?
这些路就通向矿井
These tracks lead right down to it.
沿着走就行
I mean, we just follow them.
没人会迷路
No one gets lost.
完全正确
Exactly.
就这么办
All right.
回去找贝克特和他的病人
Go get beckett and his patients.
把他们带过来  我们集中其他人
Bring them here. we'll round up everyone else.
怎么了
What is it?
肯定发生了什么事
Something's happening.
什么事
What's going on?
你们马上要转移
You'll be moving shortly.
到哪儿
Where?
你们的新家
Your new home.
战舰已经到了
The hive ship has just arrived.
等等
Wait.
我有个提议
I have a proposition for you.
你要干什么  塞法里斯
What are you doing, sefaris?
有些事很早前我们就该做了
Something we should have done a long time ago.
你没什么我想要的
There is nothing you have to offer me.
别那么肯定
Don't be so sure.
村子里藏着个人
There's someone hiding in the village.
他比我们所有人的价值都大
He's of far greater value than all of us put together.
塞法里斯  不行...
Sefaris, no--
放了我们  我就带你去
Spare our lives, I'll take you to him.
提议不错
A fair attempt...
但我的答案是  不
But the answer's no.
那就放了我
My life, then.
你怎么能这么做
How could you do this?
我保证  你们的等待绝对值得
I promise, it'll be worth your while.
我想所有人都在这儿了
I believe that is everybody.
麦凯和贝克特在哪里
Where's mckay and beckett?
罗德尼  你那边情况怎么样
Rodney, what's your status?
还在医务室
Still at the clinic.
卡森决定再带点东西
Carson decided to pick up a few more supplies.
叫他快点
Tell him to get a move on.
我们不能待很久
We can't stay here forever.
中校  你们先走
Go ahead, colonel.
我们会追上来的
We'll catch up.
你肯定?
You sure?
绝对肯定  我们就跟在你们后面
Absolutely. we'll be right behind you.
我们出发
Let's get going.
跟紧了  沿着路走
Stay together. follow the tracks.
那儿  那应该行
There. that should do it.
罗德尼  能不能帮个忙
Rodney, can you give me a hand here?
记得提醒我  下次来的时候带个夏尔巴人
Remind me to bring a sherpa next time I visit.
他
Him.
他就是那个人
He's the one.
你瞧
You see?
我遵守了我的约定
I kept up my end of the bargain.
的确
So you did.
但很不幸
Unfortunately,
基于你的
In light of your...
情况
"condition"...
留你活口太危险了
Keeping you alive is far too risky.
幽灵战斗机
Darts.
罗德尼和卡森还没来
Rodney and carson are still not here.
罗德尼  请回话
Rodney, come in.
麦凯
Mckay?
你们继续走
You guys keep moving.
我回去接应他
I'm going to go get him.
若楠  泰勒
Ronon? teyla?
请说
Go ahead.
幽灵人抓了贝克特和麦凯
The wraith just got beckett and mckay.
什么  怎么会
What? how?
他们被带到幽灵战斗机上
Took 'em up in a dart.
我想他们是要被送到战舰上
I think they're on their way up to a hive.
幽灵是怎么知道他们在村里的
How did the wraith know that they were in the village?
我想我有点头绪
I think I got an idea.
罗德尼
Rodney.
罗德尼  醒醒
Rodney, wake up.
我的上帝  这是我么
Oh... god, is it me,
还是他们的电晕武器加了电量
Or have they juiced up the stun weapons?
他们还把我们带到了战舰上
Oh, and they brought us to the hive.
真是太好了
That's great.
我们怎么办
What are we going to do?
别  别惊慌
Uh, just don't-- don't panic.
别惊慌
Don't panic.
我对逃离这种地方很有经验
I have... got lots of experience escaping from these things.
你?
You do?
是啊
Oh, yeah. yeah.
这种情况  我碰到过几十次了
I've been in this situation dozens of times,
总能找到出去的方法
Always figured a way out.
具体怎么办
How, exactly?
让我想想
Uh, let's see.
上一次  泰勒冒充女皇  所以...
Last time, teyla was posing as a queen, so...
然后  她把我们放了
You know, she had us released.
这次不太可能
Not much chance of that happening.
我猜也不行
No, I guess not.
那再上次呢
How about the time before that?
若楠的朋友泰尔假装成
Ronon's friend tyre was pretending to be
幽灵人的同盟军
In league with the wraith,
但事实上他是我们这边的  所以...
But really he was on our side, so...
他放了我们
He let us out.
我想我看出规律了
I'm starting to sense a pattern here.
事实上  你从来没有
You've actually never really
靠自己逃出这种监狱过
Escaped from one of these cells on your own?
凡事都有第一次
First time for everything, right?
我的上帝  罗德尼
Oh, god, rodney.
好了  给我一分钟
Well, just... give me a minute.
让我想想怎么办
I'll think of something.
我不想给你压力  罗德尼
I hate to pressure you, rodney,
但我想我们连一分钟都没了
But I don't think we have a minute.
把他们带出来
Bring them.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
我的顶级科学家用的实验室
A lab belonging to my top scientist.
过去6个月他一直在研究
For the last six months he has been studying
渗入到
The deadly toxin
我们食物中的剧毒
That has infiltrated our food supply.
他现在人呢
Where is he now?
死了
Dead.
他确信
He was convinced
自己找到了一种安全可行的方法
He had arrived at a foolproof way
来检测毒药
To detect the poison.
为了证明这点
To prove it, he decided
他决定以身试药
To feed on one of his test subjects.
我猜结果没用
Guess that didn't work out so well?
他在痛苦中死去
He died in excruciating pain.
更不用说
Needless to say,
他的研究就此止步
His research has been stalled ever since.
所以你们才会在这儿
And that's where you come in,
医生
Doctor.
我?
Me?
你想让我干嘛
What do you expect me to do?
指认你的人说
The one who identified you said
你在处理毒药方面经验颇丰
You had considerable expertise in dealing with the toxin.
他甚至说你有参与研究它
He even said you had a hand in developing it.
如果有谁能找到
If anyone can find
检测毒药的方法  那就是你
A way to detect it, you can.
如果你觉得我能帮到你
If you think I'm going to help you,
你就大错特错了
You're sorely mistaken.
我预测到你会这么说
I anticipated you might say that,
所以我为你准备了
Which is why I'm prepared
一点奖励
To offer you an incentive.
目前为止
Thus far,
我决定放过下面星球上的人们
I have spared the lives of the people on the planet below.
如果你合作  我就继续这么做
If you cooperate, I will continue to do so.
如果你们任何一个惹火我
But if either of you try to cross me in any way--
好好好  我们明白了
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, we get the picture.
我就知道你们会明白的
I knew you'd come to see it my way.
开始吧
Get to work.
给我个不打爆你头的理由
Give me one reason why I shouldn't Blow your head off.
为什么
What for?
幽灵人怎么会去抓贝克特的
How did the wraith know to grab beckett?
你什么意思
W-what do you mean?
医生被抓了?
Doctor's been captured?
我发誓  和我没关系
I swear, I had nothing to do with that.
那你的人呢
What about your men?
也没有
No.
绝不可能
No, there's no way.
医生对我们一向很好
The doctor has been nothing but good to us.
他们不可能是碰巧去医务室的
Well, they didn't just stumble across the clinic.
一定有人带他们过去
Somebody brought them there.
你为什么不问问巴拉人
Well, why don't you ask the balarans?
他们最有利益可图
They're the ones with the most to gain.
他们中可能有人觉得
One of them probably thought
交出医生能换自己一命
He could save himself by turning in the doctor.
我告诉过你他们不是好人  中校
I told you they were no good, colonel.
该死
Damn it.
这些仪器没一个能连上
None of these consoles are hooked into anything.
我没法进入任何一个飞船系统
I can't access any of the ship's systems.
你呢
What about you?
有没有什么进展
You making any progress?
卡森
Carson?
你还好吧
You okay?
我办不到  罗德尼
I can't do this, rodney.
什么意思
What do you mean?
还没明白吗
You don't understand it?
不是  我是说  我做不到
No. I mean, I can't do it.
要是幽灵人找到检测hoffan药的方法
Do you realize what'll happen
你知道会有什么后果吗
If the wraith find a way to detect the hoffan drug?
他们会将整个银河系里
They'll hunt down
带毒的人全部歼灭殆尽
Every last person in this galaxy that has it.
那可是成千上万的人啊  罗德尼
That's hundreds of thousands of people, rodney.
更不用说当他们杀完后
Not to mention the fact that, when they're finished,
就会随心所欲地四处捕食
They can start feeding again, indiscriminately.
还有其它选择吗
What's the alternative, huh?
我们都知道幽灵人
We know the wraith
是不会就此罢休的
Aren't just going to let the matter drop.
我们都见识过他们的行径
We've seen what they can do.
他们会彻底摧毁整个村庄
They'll-- they'll wipe out entire villages
只是为了抓到几个巴拉星人
Just to get a few like the balarans.
那我要怎么做
So what am I supposed to do?
拖延时间就行了
You just stall.
假装你在干活
You know, you make it look like you're working, and...
直到我们找到逃跑的办法
Till we figure out how to get the hell out of here.
之后呢  继续做我们的事
And then what? go about our business?
假装一切从来没发生过吗
Pretend this never happened?
我没说这件事很容易
I never said it was going to be easy.
你不可能把银河系的所有问题
But you can't solve all the galaxy's problems
在一天内解决
In one day.
听着  我理解
Look, I understand.
你有罪恶感
You feel guilty.
但这不是你的错
But this is not your fault.
你又不知道事情会这样
You had no idea that any of this was going to happen.
医学院里老师教我们的第一件事
One of the first things they taught us in medical school
就是"不要害人"
Was "do no harm."
这种情况下我都不知道怎么做
Now, I'm at a loss right now
才能算是不去害人
To figure out how that's even possible in this situation.
他们怎么样了
How are they doing?
惊吓过度
They are frightened.
我一直试着让他们放心
I've been trying to reassure them,
不过没什么用
But it is of little use.
情况怎么样
How's it going in here?
勉强应付
We are getting by.
村里发生什么事了
What is happening in the village?
没啥  人人都躲在家里
Ah, not much. everybody's hiding indoors.
蜂巢战舰为啥还没开始进攻
Why hasn't the hive ship attacked yet?
你觉得这跟罗德尼和卡森的被俘
Do you think it could have something to do
有什么关系么
With rodney and carson's capture?
不清楚
I don't know,
不过我们应该利用现在的时间定个计划
But we should use this time to come up with a plan.
你有主意了?
You got anything?
算是吧  但是得费点事
Maybe, but it's going to take some work.
那是啥  发现什么了吗
What is it? you got something?
没有
No.
你确定
You sure?
你的脸上又浮现了"贝克特式"经典表情
You got one of those "beckett" faces.
有吗  真没啥  罗德尼
Aye, I'm sure, rodney.
回去做事吧
Just go back to work.
你去哪儿
Where are you going?
跟蜂巢战舰指挥官谈谈
To talk to the hive commander.
什么
What?
为什么
Why?
有点事得和他说下
There's something I need to tell him.
明白了  你发现什么了  到底是什么
Oh, I knew it. you found something. what is it?
开门
Hey, open up!
说真的  能告诉我吗
Seriously, will you just tell me?
你知道一旦你离开
You know I'm going to go through your stuff
我就会查看你的东西的
As soon as you're gone.
别管我了  罗德尼  开门
Just leave me be, rodney. open the door!
告诉我怎么回事不行吗
Will you just tell me what's going on?
我得马上跟指挥官谈谈
I need to talk to the commander right away.
听着  罗德尼  我要你待在这
Listen to me, rodney. I need you to stay here.
别担心
Don't worry.
不会有事的
Everything will be just fine.
走吧
Right.
医生
Doctor.
没想到那么快就有消息了
I didn't expect to hear from you so soon.
一定是好事吧
This must be good news.
对有些人来说  可能是的
For some people, maybe.
我来是告诉你我不干了
I'm here to tell you that I'm off the case.
你说什么
What are you talking about?
我不会再为你做那些龌龊的事了
I'm not going to do your dirty work for you.
另请高明吧
Find someone else.
没人可以代替你
There is no one else!
那只能算你运气不好啦
Then that's too bad for you, isn't it?
你在试探我的耐心  医生
You're trying my patience, doctor.
别忘了
You forget,
我手里握着下面那些人的性命
I control the fate of the people below.
无论我怎么做他们都会死的
People will die no matter what I do,
所以我什么都不会做
So I'm not going to do anything.
如果你拒绝完成这次研究
If you refuse to complete the research,
那你对我来说
Then there is only one other way
就只有另外一种用途了
That you could be of use to me.
相信我
And, trust me,
你不会喜欢的
You won't like it.
别再吓唬我了
You don't scare me anymore.
还不明白吗
Do you understand?
你怎么做都没用
I don't give a damn what you do to me.
随便你
Suit yourself.
我会非常享受的
I'm going to enjoy this... very much.
这是什么
What is this?
你对我做了什么
What have you done to me?
想不到你们距离检测出hoffan药
Turns out you were closer
只有一步之遥了
To detecting the hoffan drug than you thought.
完善你们的血液测试并没有花费多大功夫
It didn't take me long to perfect your blood test.
用你们提供的样品
And once I confirmed it
确认完以后
Using samples that you provided,
我决定拿我自己再做一次试验
I decided to do one more test,
以便万无一失
Just to be certain... on me.
你有毒素
You have the toxin?
说对了
Indeed.
现在  你也有了
And now... so do you.
卡森
Carson!
罗德尼
Hello, rodney.
你能删了那些数据吗
Can you delete this data?
当然  不过你怎么
Yeah, of course, but how did you--
我引诱指挥官吸食我
I talked the hive commander into feeding on me.
什么  什么
What? what?
为什么那么做
Why would you do that?
我有hoffan药  罗德尼
I have the hoffan drug, rodney.
一定是在和幽灵人作战的时候迈克尔给我的
Michael must have given it to me as a defense against the wraith.
为什么你没告诉我
Well, why didn't you tell me?
因为你会阻止我的
Because you would have stopped me from going.
是  因为那么做太蠢了
Yeah, because it's stupid!
要是你错了怎么办
What would've happened if you were wrong?
我得做点什么
I had to do something.
这是我们逃走的唯一机会
It's the only chance we had to get away.
现在你能在他们发现之前
Now, will you help me destroy this research
毁了这些研究资料吗
Before they find out what I've done?
可以
Right.
太棒了
Okay, great.
此路安全
The coast is clear.
我们到底在干嘛
What are we doing, exactly?
你说呢
What do you think?
我们在找飞船的出口
We're looking for a way off this ship.
就在走廊里漫无目的地晃悠?
By wandering aimlessly through the hallways?
我不是漫无目的地晃悠
I'm not wandering aimlessly.
我是在探索
I'm exploring.
两者差别很大的
There's a big difference.
找到了
Bingo!
你干什么呢  罗德尼
What are you doing, rodney?
侵入飞船的通讯系统
Hacking into the ship's communications.
你确定这么做好吗
Are you sure that's a good idea?
听着  要是不先联系上谢帕德
Look, if we don't get in touch with sheppard,
我们就别想离开飞船
We don't stand any chance of getting off this ship.
你得掩护我
You're going to have to cover me.
对
All right.
从哪个方向
From which direction?
那是什么
What was that?
谢帕德  听到了吗
Sheppard, do you read me?
麦凯  是你吗
Mckay, is that you?
谢天谢地
Oh! thank god!
我们在蜂巢战舰上  和贝克特一起
Okay, we are on the hive ship. I've got beckett with me.
到底怎么了
What the hell is going on up there?
我们试着逃跑
We managed to escape.
贝克特帮了大忙
Beckett helped.
太好了
Oh, that's great,
终于有救兵了
'cause we could really use the help.
你
You?
被困在船上的是我们
Look, we're the ones stuck on the ship!
现在需要你们在飞船上
That's exactly where you need to be right now,
因为我们需要有人
Because we need someone
除去蜂巢战舰的主要武器
To take out the hive's main weapons.
什么
What?
我们做了个计划
We got a plan,
不过只有先把蜂巢战舰搞垮
But it's only going to work
计划才能实施
If we take the hive out of the picture.
侵入通讯系统就已经够糟的了
It is bad enough that I hacked into communications!
要是再闯进别的系统
If I start messing around with other systems,
他们肯定会在几分钟内找到我们的
They'll track us down in a matter of minutes!
罗德尼  这是救其他人的
Rodney, it's the only way
唯一办法
To get these people to safety.
一旦结束
Once that's done,
我们就会想办法去救你们
We'll figure out a way to get you guys out of there.
好吧
All right.
看看我能做什么  给我几分钟的时间
I'll see what I can do. give me a few minutes.
应该就够了
That should be enough time.
你真是个好人  罗德尼
You're a good man, rodney.
是啊  是啊
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
别忘了我们就行了
Just don't forget us, okay?
不会的  祝你们好运
We won't. good luck.
你觉得他能搞定吗
Think he'll be able to pull it off?
最好能
Well, he'd better.
否则  事情就会变得非常糟了
Otherwise this thing's going to go very badly.
杰维斯
Jervis.
想干嘛
What do you want?
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
和你没什么好谈的
Well, I have nothing to say to you.
你一直都是对的
You were right all along.
我应该听你的
I should have listened to you.
亚特兰蒂斯人根本不知道他们在干嘛
The atlantians have no idea what they're doing.
他们说是已经有了计划  实际上
They claim to have a plan, but, in reality,
只是拿我们的性命
They're just putting
去冒险
All our lives at risk.
现在有点太迟了  不是吗
It's a little late now, isn't it?
不一定
Is it?
如果你现在去星门那儿找幽灵人
If you went to the wraith at the gate right now,
你觉得他们会遵守原先的承诺吗
Do you think you could get them to honor the original deal?
有可能的
It's possible.
但是
But...
我得立刻交出
I'd have to deliver
剩下的所有外来者
All of the remaining outsiders at once.
他们在矿山里
They're in the mine,
藏在主室
Hiding in the main chamber.
其他村里的议员也同意吗
Are the other councilors on board with this?
他们知道得越少越好
The less they know about it, the better.
你呢
And you?
你对得起你的良心吗
Can you reconcile this with your conscience?
这不用你担心
Leave that to me.
你搞定交易就好
You just make that deal.
怎么回事
What is it?
搜索飞船
Search the ship.
这得花多久  罗德尼
How long is this going to take, rodney?
你在做手术时
Do I rush you
我有催过你么
While you're performing complicated surgery?
我知道你会催的
Aye, it's been known to happen.
好了  搞定了
All right, I'm in.
现在给我几分钟时间来解除
Now, I just need a few minutes to disable the--
老天哪
Oh, geez!
我们被发现了
I think they found us!
你说呢
You figure?
你得把他们牵制住
Okay, you're going to have to hold them off.
我?  现在?
Am i, now?
就是你  上吧
Yeah. come on, carson.
你能行的  好吧
You can do this, all right?
好吧  我数到三
All right. on three?
数到一就好了
How about on one?
好吧  好吧
All right. right.
一
And, one!
怎么样了
How's it coming?
差不多了
Almost there.
我不能一直拖住他们  罗德尼
I can't hold them off forever, rodney!
我们得走了  立刻
We have to go! now!
好了  搞定了  走吧走吧
All right, that's it! I got it! let's go!
我们去哪儿
Where are we going?
战机停靠处
The dart bay.
你知道怎么开幽灵战斗机
You know how to fly a dart?
我以前开过飞船
Well, I've flown jumpers before.
我去过东京
I've been to tokyo before.
并不意味着我会说日语啊
Doesn't mean I can speak japanese.
能有多难啊
Well, how hard can it be?
你到底知不知道自己去哪儿
Do you even know where you're going?
知道啊  我从控制台
Yeah, I pulled up
扯了张飞船示意图
A schematic of the ship on that console.
什么  在我们被袭击的时候?
What? while we were being fired upon?
好了  锁上了
All right, that's sealed.
这能拖住他们多久
How long do you think it'll hold them?
不太久
Not very.
来吧
Well, come on.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
挤进来
I'm getting in.
容不下我们两个的
Well, we can't both fit in here.
一点没错  往旁边去点
You're damn right I can. now shove over!
你很舒服吧
You comfy?
爽呆了
Peachy.
你还在等什么
What are you waiting for?
应该起飞了啊
Well, it should just start up.
它怎么没反应
Well, it didn't.
我知道  这不对啊
I know, but it doesn't make sense.
我们头顶应该形成顶篷
A canopy should form over our head.
难到还有重量限制
Maybe there's some kind of a weight limit?
这是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
我是说这儿多了个人
I mean because there's two of us!
可能要用钥匙什么的
Well, maybe you need a key, or something?
这可不是大众汽车
It's not a volkswagen, carson!
听着
Okay, look,
显然是飞船操作系统
These are obviously the flight controls.
推进飞船前进
That makes that propulsion, so...
如此绝妙的结论哪儿来的
Where'd you come up with that brilliant conclusion?
这是常识
It's just common sense!
给点反应
Come on!
是啊  常识而已
Right, common sense.
我能怎么样
What do you want from me?
上面又没贴标签
It's not like there's labels!
大事不妙了
Oh, not good!
一点没错
You're telling me.
重想个计划  罗德尼
We need a new plan, rodney.
我当然知道  我在想啊
I know! I'm thinking!
总之  快想
Well, whatever you do, think fast,
只要幽灵突破了这道门  我们就挂定了
Because if those wraith come through that door, we both dead
罗德尼  我们得走了
Rodney, we need to go.
去哪儿  我们被困住了
Where? I mean, we're trapped in here!
那也得找个地方藏身啊
Then we need to find a place to hide.
快点
Come on.
怎么了
What?
我有主意了
I have another idea.
成功机会渺茫  但总得试试
It's a long shot, but it might work.
你得先从我身边挪开
But you're going to have to get off me!
一旦你带上他们
Once you've taken these people,
就会离开村庄  对吧
You're going to leave the village, right?
永远的
For good?
这个地方对我们没有意义
This place is of no concern to us.
我们只想得到巴拉人
All we want is the balarans.
前面有个大房间
There's a large chamber up ahead.
他们就藏在那里
That's where they're hiding.
他们在哪
Where are they?
我也不知道
I don't understand.
他说他们在这儿的
He said they were here!
我...他们应该就在这儿
I... they should be right here!
这是什么
What is this?
杀了这么多幽灵
Think we killed enough wraith
有用么
To make a difference?
走着瞧
Guess we'll find out.
干得漂亮
Nice work.
我们收到消息
We've received word
地面上发生爆炸
Of an explosion on the planet
我们不少战士因此丧生
That's killed several of our warriors.
人类不断袭击我们的部队
The humans continue to attack our troops.
他们要逃跑
They're trying to escape.
瞄准星门附近的地区
Target the area around the portal
开火
And open fire.
武器没反应
Weapons aren't responding!
什么
What?
拨号星门
Dial the gate.
这只是先遣部队  还会有更多
This is the first group. there are more are coming.
快点行动
We've got to move fast.
他们可不会中途躺下休息
They won't take this lying down.
出发
Let's go.
好的  来吧  出发
All right. come on, let's go.
弯腰  低一点
Stay low, stay low.
我们和把守星门的部队失去联系了
We've lost contact with the troops at the gate.
那两个人类囚犯呢
What about the two human prisoners?
不见了
They're nowhere to be seen.
他们不可能就这么消失了
They couldn't have just disappeared.
不过没关系
It doesn't matter.
不能让村民逃了
We can't let the villagers escape.
启动飞船
Launch the darts.
中校
Colonel!
快走  快走
Go, go, go!
该死的
Oh, crap!
谢帕德  又有人来了
Sheppard! we've got more coming!
快点  就快到了
Go, go, go! you're almost there.
泰勒
Teyla!
罗德尼  卡森
Rodney! carson!
老天哪  成功了
Oh, my god, it worked!
你简直是天才
Rodney, you're a genius!
你做了什么
What'd you do?
我重新设定了选择性电波使我们消失
I reprogrammed the culling beam to dematerialize us,
然后使其仅在一点释放
Then to discharge only from that point on.
一旦幽灵失去了他们的主武器
Once the wraith lost their main weapons,
启动飞船只是时间的问题
It was just a matter of time for them to launch the darts.
出发
Let's go!
你终于出现了
There you are!
我一直在呼叫你
I've been calling you.
对不起  什么事
Oh, I'm sorry. what's up?
罗恩他们为村民找到了一个
Lorne's team just found a suitable planet
合适的星球
For the villagers.
他们下午就搬过去了
They're going to move them out this afternoon.
我听说了  我和他们一起走
Aye, I heard. I'm going with them.
是啊  当然
Oh, right.Of course.
要不要一起吃顿午饭
Um, well, you want to... grab some lunch?
我们还没时间唠唠嗑呢
We didn't get any chance to socialize this time around,
除非算上
Unless you count, you know,
在蜂巢战舰大厅转悠的时候
Running through the halls of the hive ship as social time.
是啊
Aye, you're right.
罗德尼  我很愿意
Look, rodney, I'd love to,
但我得先搞定这个
But I really need to get through this.
这是什么
Well, what is it?
凯勒医生关于血清的研究
Dr. keller's research on the serum
防止我的细胞持续恶化
That keeps my cells from deteriorating.
我想对那些在瘟疫中幸存下来的人
I think there might be something in here
可能有帮助
To help the plague survivors,
我已经不再感染了  而他们还在
Since I'm not getting the infections that they are.
你不用现在做啊
Well, you don't have to do this now.
要是我的话  会下到硬盘里
I'll download the data to a drive.
你带走就是了
You can just, you know, take it with you.
事实上不行
Actually, you can't.
伍尔希先生不想让数据离开基地
Mr. woolsey doesn't want it leaving the base.
对不起  罗德尼
I'm sorry, rodney.
没关系  我不在意
Well, I don't care.
只是想防止你总抱怨说
I was just, you know, trying to stop you
见不到我的人影
From whining about never seeing me.
好吧
All right.
罗德尼  等等
Rodney, wait.
现在我有点饿了
Now that I think of it, I am a wee bit peckish.
另外我也不可能把银河系的所有问题
Besides, I can't solve all the galaxy's problems
在一天内解决吧
In one day, can i?
那我
Well, i--
别说了
Shut it.
好了  走吧
Right, let's go.
那么
So?
最近有没有心上人
Interested in anyone these days?
没有  没时间想那个
Me? no, I don't have time for that.
你真不会说谎  麦凯博士
You're a terrible liar, dr. mckay.
快说  快说
Tell me, tell me, tell me.